Benjamin Spock and Mary Morgan Papers
Benjamin Spock and Mary Morgan Papers
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "Bringing Up Children in an Age of Disenchantment", 1966; published in Redbook (Box 385)
    - C. Anderson Aldrich (subject), 1948; published in Mental Hygiene (Box 385)
    - "Calling Parents By First Names", 1981; published in Redbook (Box 385)
    - "Can a Mother Play a Father's Role?", 1969; published in Redbook (Box 385)
    - "Can Children Be Taught To Make Decisions?", 1974; published in Redbook (Box 385)
    - "Can Motherhood Be Taught?", 1958; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 385)
    - "Can One Parent Be as Good as Two?", 1987; published in Redbook (Box 385)
    - "Can We Protect Children From Molesters?", 1969; published in Redbook (Box 385)
    - "Can You Love All Your Children Equally?", 1956; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 385)
    - "Can You Love All Your Children The Same?", 1983; published in Redbook (Box 385)
    - "Can You Prevent Molestation and Abduction?", 1984; published in Redbook (Box 385)
    - "Can You Raise Your Child's I.Q.?", 1962; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 385)
    - "Can You Spoil a Baby?", 1993; published in Parenting Magazine (Box 385)
    - "Can You Spot a Delinquent in the Making?", 1960; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 385)
    - "The Care of Handicapped Children in the Home", 1960; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 385)
    - "Caring for Two Small Children Close in Age", 1968; published in Redbook (Box 386)
    - The Causes of War (subject), 1966 (Box 386)
    - "Character Traits Can Take a Long Time to Develop", 1968; published in Redbook (Box 386)
    - Child Development Concepts (subject), undated (Box 386)
    - "The Child Health Institute in Rochester, Minnesota" [alternate title: "Child Health Project"], 1949; published in American Journal of Public Health (Box 386)
    - "A Child Must Feel He Belongs", 1958; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 386)
    - "The Child Views God Through Parents' Eyes", 1957; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 386)
    - "The Child Who Tries to Control His Parents", 1966; published in Redbook (Box 386)
    - "The Child With One Parent", 1962; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 386)
    - "Children, Animals and Scary Stories", undated; published in Il Messengero (Box 386)
    - "Children and Death", 1969; published in Redbook (Box 386)
    - "Children and Discrimination", 1964; published in Integrated Education (Box 386)
    - "Children and Discrimination", 1964; published in Redbook (Box 386)
    - "Children of Divorced Parents", 1975; review of Part-Time Father by Atkins and Rubin (Box 386)
    - "Children Need a Pole to Grow On", 1975; published in Today's Education; interview by Harold G. Shane (Box 386)
    - "Children and Pets", 1972; published in Redbook (Box 386)
    - "Children and Religion", 1991; published in Redbook (Box 386)
    - "Children, Television and 'Sesame Street' ", 1970; published in Redbook; includes letter from Sey Chassler to Spock, Margaret Mead, and T. Berry Brazelton (Box 386)
    - "Children of Vietnam", 1967; published in Ramparts; preface article and photographs by William F. Pepper (Box 386)
    - "Children's Anger at Parents", 1961; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 387)
    - "The Children's Center", 1948 (Box 387)
    - "Children's Concerns About Death", 1964; published in Redbook (Box 387)
    - "Children's Health: Accent on Emotions", 1954; published in National Parent-Teacher (Box 387)
    - "Children's Need for Roots and Repetition", 1964; published in Redbook (Box 387)
    - "A Child's Position in the Family" [co-author Marvin Shapiro], 1955; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 387)
    - "Christmas When I Was a Boy", 1980; published in Redbook (Box 387)
    - "Chronic Resistance to Sleep in Infancy", 1948; published in Pediatrics (Box 387)
    - "Circumcision - It's Not Necessary", 1989; published in Redbook (Box 387)
    - "Coercion in the Classroom Won't Work", 1984; published in The Atlantic (Box 387)
    - "Coercion or Learning By Experience?", circa 1984; published in New York Times; The Atlantic; 3 folders (Box 387)
    - "The Cold War and Children", 1964; published in Journal of Nursery Education (Box 388)
    - "Cold War - Trauma or Challenge?", 1964; published in Child Study (Box 388)
    - "Common Behavior Disturbances in the First Two Years of Life", 1948; published in Journal of the American Medical Association (Box 388)
    - "Common Sense for America", 1973; published in Grass Roots (Box 388)
    - "Communes and Nurseries: Are They as Good for Children as They are Helpful for Mothers?", 1970; published in Redbook (Box 388)
    - Communication Between Doctors, Social Workers, Teachers, etc. (subject), 1949 (Box 388)
    - "Competion", 1992; published in Parenting (Box 388)
    - "Conformity - Is There Too Much?", 1959; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 388)
    - "Consistency In Discipline", 1991; published in Redbook (Box 388)
    - "Controlling Young Children", 1966; published in Redbook (Box 388)
    - "Coping With a Child's Serious Illness", 1973; published in Redbook (Box 388)
    - "Crying in Infancy", 1966; published in Redbook (Box 388)
    - "Dealing with 6-12 Year Olds", 1959; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 388)
    - "Delinquency - Why the Increase?", 1961; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 388)
    - "Dialogue with Margaret Mead", 1972; published in Redbook (Box 388)
    - "Did I Change My Mind?", 1963; published in Redbook (Box 388)
    - "The Difference Between the Sexes", 1956; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 388)
    - "Differences Between First-Born and Other Children", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 388)
    - "Difficulties in Breast Feeding", 1964; published in Redbook (Box 388)
    - "The Differential Diagnosis of Jaundice", 1933; published in American Journal of the Medical Sciences (Box 388)
    - Discipline (subject), 1955 (Box 389)
    - "Discipline", 1983; published in Redbook (Box 389)
    - "Discipline - Brain Washing", 1960; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 389)
    - "The Discipline Survey", 1981; published in Redbook; 2 folders (Box 389)
    - "Discipline - Where Fathers Fail", 1964; published in Redbook (Box 389)
    - "Discussion with Benjamin Spock", 1974; published in Practical Psychology (Box 389)
    - "Disenchantment", 1963; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 389)
    - "Disenchantment", undated (Box 389)
    - "Do Parents Cause Children's Emotional Problems?", 1966; published in Redbook (Box 389)
    - "Do Parents Teach Prejudice?", 1962; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 389)
    - "Do Parents Teach Prejudice?", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 389)
    - "Do Your Children Worry About War?", 1962; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 389)
    - "Dr. Spock Answers", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 389)
    - "Dr. Spock Answers Your Questions" (Series), 1981; published in Redbook (Box 389)
    - "Dr. Spock Answers Your Questions About Parenting" (series), 1983; published in Redbook (Box 389)
    - "Dr. Spock in China", 1974; published in New China (Box 390)
    - "Dr. Spock is Still Worried", 1979; published in Redbook (Box 390)
    - "Dr. Spock Is Worried", 1962; published by National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (Box 390)
    - "Dr. Spock Says Common Measles Can Be Ended If Parents Will It" (Box 390)
    - "Dr. Spock Visits the Anderson Five", 1974; published in Redbook (Box 390)
    - "Dr. Spock: Seventeen Million Copies Later", 1965; published in Medical World News (Box 390)
    - "Does Your Kid Have Too Much To Do?", 1986; published in Redbook (Box 390)
    - "Does Your Second Child Feel Second Rate?", 1990; published in Redbook (Box 390)
    - "Draft Registration --For What Purpose?", 1980; published in Viewpoint Syndicate (Box 390)
    - Drug Abuse (subject) (series), 1971; published in Redbook (Box 390)
    - "Early or Late Child Bearing", 1991; published in Redbook (Box 390)
    - "Editorial in Favor of Fluoridation", undated (Box 390)
    - Education (subject), 1981; series, published in Redbook (Box 390)
    - Education (subject) [cont.], 1981; series, published in Redbook (Box 391)
    - "Education for Peace", 1975; published in Thresholds (Box 391)
    - "The Effects of Three Kinds of Discipline", 1969; published in Redbook (Box 391)
    - "El Salvador", 1981; published in Viewpoint Syndicate (Box 391)
    - "Embarrassing Birthdays and Illegitimate Births", 1966; published in Redbook (Box 391)
    - "Emotional Aspects of Breastfeeding", 1948 (Box 391)
    - "Emotional Readiness for Toilet Training", 1993; published in Parenting (Box 391)
    - "Etiological Factors in Hypertrophic Pyloric Stenosis and Infantile Colic", 1944; published in Psychomatic Medicine (Box 391)
    - "Every Child Needs a Pet", 1988; published in Redbook (Box 391)
    - "Every Child Should Have a Chore", 1987; published in Redbook (Box 391)
    - Excerpts from "Baby and Child Care", 1992; published in Redbook (Box 391)
    - "Experience with a Medical Schoool Family Study", 1961; published in Journal of Medical Education (Box 391)
    - "Explaining Death", 1960; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 391)
    - "Family Triangle: Mother and Child - And Grandmother", 1957; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 391)
    - "A Father's Companionship", 1974; published in Redbook (Box 391)
    - "A Father's Role in Discipline", 1974; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - "Fathers As Disiplinarians", 1969; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - "The First Child and His Special Position", 1957; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 392)
    - "The First Hours", 1967; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - "The First Three Months of Your Baby's Life", 1972; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - "Formulas", 1983; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - "Fostering Creativity and Imagination in Children", 1972; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - "Fresh Air", 1958; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 392)
    - "The Fuss Over 'Baby and Child Care' ", 1968; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - "Getting Along With the Middle-Aged Child", 1947; published in American Home (Box 392)
    - "Giving Children Beliefs and Ideals", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - "Going Out With Children - Without Tears", 1978; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - "Good Manners Are Often Just a Question of Taste", 1956; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 392)
    - "The Good News About How Americans Are Raising Their Children", 1983; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - "Good Ways to Handle a Child's Anger", 1989; published in Redbook (Box 392)
    - Grandparents (subject), undated; possibly published in Yale Review (Box 392)
    - "Greetings From the American Peace Movement", undated (Box 392)
    - "Grim Thoughts on the Election", 1980; published in Viewpoint Syndicate (Box 392)
    - "Guiding Your Child's Eating Habits", 1979; published in Redbook (Box 393)
    - "Happy Birthday, Dr. Spock", 1987; published in Redbook (Box 393)
    - "Have You Ever Wanted to Strike Your Child?", 1988; published in Redbook (Box 393)
    - "Health and Youth", 1953; published in Pittsburgh Sun Telegraph (Box 393)
    - "Helpfulness", 1984; published in Redbook (Box 393)
    - "Helping Children of Different Ages ro Understand Religion", 1971; published in Redbook (Box 393)
    - "Helping Children to Express Anger", 1973; published in Redbook (Box 393)
    - "Helping Children Get Along With Friends and Neighbors", 1974; published in Redbook (Box 393)
    - "Helping Children Not To Be Timid", 1974; published in Redbook (Box 393)
    - "Helping the Procrastinating Child", 1971; published in Redbook (Box 393)
    - "Helping Your Children to Learn About Money", 1967; published in Redbook (Box 393)
    - "Hesitancy", 1989; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "The High Cost of Keeping a Family Healthy", 1973; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "Honor", 1980; published in Viewpoint Syndicate (Box 394)
    - "Hostile Aggression", 1981; published in Viewpoint Syndicate (Box 394)
    - "Housekeeping and Childkeeping in the Olden Days", 1969; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How an Easier Life Can Be a Happier Life", undated; published in McCall's (Box 394)
    - "How Boys and Girls Learn to be Grownups", 1967; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How Can We Protect our Children From Oscenity?", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How Children Learn to be Grown Up", 1975 (Box 394)
    - "How Children Learn the Joy of Giving", 1967; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How Children Learn to Make Friends", 1972; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How Children Make Friends", 1975; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How Creativity and Imagination Enrich Your Child's Development", 1980; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How Democratic Should a Family Be?", 1977; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How Divorced Parents Can Help Their Children", 1977; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How Divorced Parents Can Help Their Children Adjust", 1970; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How Do I Make Him Mind?", 1956; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 394)
    - "How Do I Stand on Discipline?", 1983; published in Redbook (Box 394)
    - "How Do We Get Mental Health for Our Children?", 1953; published by National Association for Mental Health (Box 395)
    - "How Do You Explain Divorce to a Child?"", 1962; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 395)
    - "How Does a Mother Know When to Let Go?", 1978; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How Fathers Can Teach Their Children Sexual Equality", 1975; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How Firm Should You be with Adolescents?", 1967; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How Important is the Prevention of Maladjustment?", undated (Box 395)
    - "How Loving Parents Can Discipline Their Child", 1977; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How Mothers Learn to Love Their Newborn Babies", 1976; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How Much Affection Should You Show Your Children?", 1972; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How Much is Enough? How Much is Too Tough?", 1983; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How Much Should a First Baby Change a Marriage?", 1976; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How Much and What Kinds of Play Do Babies Need?", 1970; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How My Ideas About Women Have Changed", 1973; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How My Ideas Have Changed", 1963; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How My Ideas Have Changed", 1991; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How Not to Bring Up a Bratty Child", 1974; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How On-Screen Violence Hurts Your Kids", 1987; published in Redbook (Box 395)
    - "How On-Screen Violence Hurts Your Kids" [cont.], 1987; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How Open Can You Be About Sex?", 1984; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How Parents Can Control Children's Quarrels", 1968; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How Parents Can Help Adolescents Understand Sex", 1962; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 396)
    - "How Strict should Parents Be?", 1975; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How To Argue With Your Child - and Win", 1978; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How To Be a Grandparent", 1971; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How To Comfort a Crying Baby", 1978; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How To Control Your Child", 1954; published in American Weekly (Box 396)
    - "How To Get Your Child to Listen", 1978; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How To Hande a Bossy Grandmother", 1989; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How To Handle a Whining Child", 1979; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How To Have Happy Children at Christmas", 1975; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How To Help the Overly Sensitive Child", 1990; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How To Keep Kids Safe in a Dangerous World", 1984; published in Redbook (Box 396)
    - "How To Prevent the Harm of Prejudice", 1981; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "How To Raise a Healthy Child", 1985; published in Redbook; interview by Jurate Kazickas (Box 397)
    - "How To Raise Children for the Twenty-First Century", 1970; published in The Mainichi Newspapers (Box 397)
    - "How To Rate Your Child's Teacher", 1986; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "How To Tame a Bully", 1986; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "How Well Nourished Should Our Children Be?", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "How You Can Ease Family Tensions", 1978; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "How Young Parents Can Get Along with Grandparents", 1971; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "How Your Child Disciplines himself", 1954; published in American Weekly (Box 397)
    - "However Good a Child's Intentions, He's Still a Child", 1956; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 397)
    - "Hurry! Hurry! Hurry!", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "I Didn't Know How to Be a Stepfather", 1985; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "The Important Part of Sex Education", 1968; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "Impressions of the DRV and China", 1973; published in Grass Roots; includes published issues (Box 397)
    - "The Impulse to Hurt a Child", 1983; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "In and on the Water", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 397)
    - "Inadequate Protection from Test Fallout", 1963 (Box 397)
    - "Independence Comes From Security as Well as Freedom", 1955; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 397)
    - "Independence in a Two Year Old", 1957 (Box 397)
    - "Infants' Illness", 1961; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 397)
    - "Innate Inhibition of Aggressiveness in Infancy", 1965; published in The Psychoanalytic Study of the Child (Box 398)
    - "Intellect Versus Feelings", published in Parenting (Box 398)
    - "Interview: Benjamin Spock, M.D.", 1969; published in The New Physician; interview by Lawrence B. Brilliant (Box 398)
    - "Iran in Retrospect", 1981; published in Viewpoint Syndicate (Box 398)
    - "Is the Breast-Fed Baby More Secure Than the Bottle-Fed?", 1955; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 398)
    - "Is Spanking Necessary ?", 1954; published in American Weekly (Box 398)
    - "Is Your Child Too Dependent on You?", 1987; published in Redbook (Box 398)
    - "Issues in Custody by Homosexual Parents", 1980 (Box 398)
    - "It's All Up To Us", 1989; published in Newsweek (Box 398)
    - "Joint Custody and the Father's Role", 1979; published in Redbook; 2 folders (Box 398)
    - "Just a Housewife", 1951; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 398)
    - "Keep Him Quietly in Bed for a Couple Days Longer - But How?", 1958; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 398)
    - "Keeping Holidays Peaceful", 1975; published in Redbook (Box 398)
    - "Kent State Ten Years Later", 1980 (Box 398)
    - "Kinds of Rebellion in Adolescence", 1966; published in Redbook (Box 398)
    - "Learning to Be a Father for the First Time", 1978; published in Redbook (Box 398)
    - "Learning to Live in a Troubled World", 1964; published in Redbook (Box 399)
    - "Lend a Helping Hand", 1982; published in Redbook (Box 399)
    - "Letter From a Divorced Young Mother", 1975; published in Redbook (Box 399)
    - "Letters on Breast-Feeding and Weaning", undated (Box 399)
    - "A Little Excitement Goes a Long Way", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 399)
    - "Loss of Freedom in Parenthood", 1957; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 399)
    - "Love and Good Behavior", 1976; published in Redbook (Box 399)
    - "Loving One Child Less", 1989; published in Redbook (Box 399)
    - "Making the Holidays Pleasant for Children and Their Parents", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 399)
    - "Manifesto", 1968 (Box 399)
    - "March on Washington", 1965; may have been a speech; unclear (Box 399)
    - "The Meaning of Love and Sex for Teenagers", undated (Box 399)
    - "The Meaning of Young Children's Fears", 1959; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 399)
    - "Medical Care for the Aged - What Young Families Should Know", 1964; published in Redbook (Box 399)
    - "Medical Education", 1980; published in Redbook (Box 399)
    - "Mental Health for Children", undated (Box 399)
    - "Messiness From Infancy to Adolescence", 1963; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 399)
    - "The Middle Aged Child" [co-author Mildred L. Hathaway or Mildred Kaye ], 1947; published in The Pennsylvania Medical Journal (Box 399)
    - Milk (subject), 1993; may be draft of some other article (Box 399)
    - "Misconceptions About China", [1973?] (Box 399)
    - "Mommy, Can I Sleep in Your Bed?", 1984; published in Redbook (Box 399)
    - "Montessori and the Traditional American Nursery Schools", 1967; published in Redbook (Box 400)
    - "Most Babies Must Put Things in Their Mouths", 1954; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 400)
    - "A Mother's Questions About Raising Quadruplets", 1966; published in Redbook (Box 400)
    - "Mothers Need a Break", 1958; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 400)
    - "Mothers of Twins Have to Find Shortcuts", 1957; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 400)
    - "Mothers' Questions About Anger", 1965; published in Redbook (Box 400)
    - "Mothers Who Try to Be All Things", 1969; published in Redbook (Box 400)
    - "My Checkered Career", undated (Box 400)
    - "My Child Won't Eat", 1955; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 400)
    - "My First Civil Disobedience", 1988 (Box 400)
    - "My Harvard, My Yale", 2000; undated (Box 400)
    - "My Opposition to Nuclear Arms" (Box 400)
    - "My Personal Crusade Against War", 1966; published in Pageant (Box 400)
    - "My Personal Politics", 1981; published in Viewpoint Syndicate (Box 400)
    - "My Pet Theory", 1990; published in Redbook (Box 400)
    - "My Visit With the Children of China", 1973; published in Redbook (Box 400)
    - "National Free Health Care Campaign Begins", 1973; published in Grass Roots; interview by Jim McClellan (Box 400)
    - "Natural Childbirth", 1956; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 400)
    - "The Need to Control Aggression in Young Children", 1968; published in Redbook (Box 400)
    - "The Neighbors' Children: Visiting Angels or Imps?", 1957; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 400)
    - "Neurosis of the Cold War", undated (Box 400)
    - "A New Awareness of an Age-Old Concern", 1956; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 400)
    - "New Baby - Rival or Responsibility?", 1957; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 400)
    - "New Parents' Self Doubts", 1973; published in Redbook (Box 401)
    - "Night Waking", 1982; published in Redbook (Box 401)
    - "Nuclear Disarmament", 1979; published in Redbook (Box 401)
    - "Nuclear War", 1980; published in East West Journal (Box 401)
    - "Obscenity", undated; published in Civil Liberties [?] (Box 401)
    - "Observations in a Foreign Land", 1978; published in Redbook (Box 401)
    - "Observations on the Striving for Autonomy and Some Regressive Object Relations After Six Months of Age", undated (Box 401)
    - "The Occasions When Feeding Problems Begin", 1948 (Box 401)
    - "Oedipus Complex", 1959; published in Ladies Home Journal; three-part series (Box 401)
    - "Office Visits", 1961; published in Ladies Home Journal (Box 401)
    - "The 'Older' Mother", 1969; published in Redbook (Box 401)
    - "On Being a Parent …of a Handicapped Child", 1961; published by The National Society for Crippled Children and Adults (Box 401)
    - "An Open Letter to George McGovern", 1972; published in Grass Roots; published version only (Box 401)
    - "An Open Letter to George McGovern", 1972; published in The Progressive; published version only (Box 401)
    - "Our Inadequate System for Fallout Countermeasures", 1962 (Box 401)
    - "Our Policies Shape the Next Generation", 1963 (Box 401)